Samantha Sanders

Front-end Developer

samantha.k.sanders@gmail.com

+64 22 317 3321

With a background in graphic design, I enjoy working closely with designers so that together we can craft beautiful and simple user experiences people will love.

I'm particularly interested in creating scalable, maintainable CSS architectures and dedicated to making experiences that are accessible and easy to use for everyone.

Key skills

- Excellent at creating scalable, maintainable CSS architectures (using BEM and ITCSS methodologies).
- Highly accomplished and focused on building accessible user experiences.
- Passionate about building rich interactions through CSS and progressively enhanced vanilla JavaScript.
- Proficient at working with various templating languages (Jinja2, Django, React/JSX).
- Experience writing ES6+ JavaScript, React, Typescript, using Node-based tooling (Babel, module bundlers).
- Comfortable conducting staff/client training and peer code reviews.
- Enjoy sharing my expertise with others in order to collaboratively craft and improve beautiful and usable experiences.
- Experience with build tools and pre-/post-processors yarn/npm, Webpack, Sass.
- Version control via Git issue trackers and pull requests.
- · Familiarity with Python, Django, Wagtail CMS and PHP.
- Happy interacting with key staff and clients to provide meaningful design and technical insight in order to deliver the best experience for all users.

Employment history

Senior Front-end Developer, The Co-operative Bank, Wellington

Sept 2019 - now

I work on the newly created front-end team, helping to establish a component library as we migrate legacy apps onto newer React based platforms.

As part of the migration process I'm focused on crafting the UI in the most usable and accessible manner as well as creating maintainable CSS architectures.

Senior Front-end Developer, Kiwi Wealth, Wellington

Feb 2019 - Sept 2019

I established the build and integration of Kiwi Wealth's new component library.

It consists of a React/Typescript UI component library, a prototyping sandpit and documentation for how to use these new tools and processes. An essential part of this role was to teach the team how to keep building on this future friendly foundation so that the benefits of having a resuable base can be felt by both the organisation and the end user.

Front-end Lead, Springload, Wellington

Aug 2013 - Jul 2018

I built front-end code for responsive websites and applications, helped a growing front-end team write scalable maintainable CSS, and ensured projects were built in an accessible and progressively enhanced manner. Key projects include the New Zealand Red Cross, ACC, Kiwibank, New Zealand Festival and RealMe.

Web Developer, Spark Digital, Melbourne

Aug 2012 - Jul 2013

Responsible for building responsive websites, Facebook applications, email templates, and Word-Press content management systems. We were a very small team so it was important for me to be on top of new technologies and ideas as the industry developed. This helped me collaborate with our designer to provide better project design concepts.

Analyst & Graphic Designer, McNamara Research, Wellington

Aug 2011 - May 2012

Monitoring and analysis of conventional communications data for government and private sector clients, as well as the design and layout of formal reports to be presented to those clients.

Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design

Canterbury University, 2007-2010

Diploma of Web Development

Natcoll Design Technology, 2011–2012